Guide to the Stanford Museum Collection
Stanford University Library
- Museum objects
  - Water Color, Zoological Lab, by E.H. Mitchell, 24x30 cm. framed under glass-51x46x2 cm. Artist signed 1897. Appraisal on back: 400$., ARCH-AM-2000-115 (Box 1)
  - Watercolor by D. S. Jordan: reptile with poem, 3/28/10, framed, ARCH-AM-1985-06 (Box 1)
  - Watercolor painting by David Starr Jordan, with poem "My Little Potamus and I". Dedicated to Maman Louise Horton March 30, 1909.Framed, ARCH-AM-2005-004 (Box 1)
  - Wells Fargo safe that once housed the gold spike, ARCH-AM-2009-024 (Box 1)
  - White hard hat and commemorative shovel from the topping out ceremony in Green West, March 27, 1998, ARCH-AM-1998-005 (Box 1)
    98-005.1 hard hat with label; 98-005.2 shovel with metal label
  - White plastic hardhard, with "Team Stanford Mansion" on back and "The Leland Stanford Mansion" with image on front, ARCH-AM-2006-024 (Box 1)
  - Window decals (3) on sheet - University seal, "S" with tree superimposed, "S" with "Cardinal" in script over it [2 sheets], ARCH-AM-2001-25 (Box 1)
  - Wine Bottle, ARCH-AM-2000-172 (Box 1)
  - Wine bottle - Stanford Alumni Association 1989 Napa Valley Cabernet Sauvignon. Label uses LSJU monogram from the cover of the SU founding grant., ARCH-AM-2006-013 (Box 1)
  - Wine bottle from Palo Alto vineyard, "Angelica", 1890, ARCH-AM-1995-13 (Box 1)
  - wine bottle: Stanford Alumni Association. 1995 Archero Winery, Paso Robles. Petite Sirah. Estate Bottled. This wine was specially selected by the Stanford Alumni Association... Includes a label with an image of the Old Union., ARCH-AM-2000-009 (Box 1)
  - Wine bottle: Stanford Alumni Association. 1992 Pedroncelli Dry Creek Sauvignon Raymond Burr Vineyards. Label includes the LSJU monogram from the Founding Grant., ARCH-AM-1999-001 (Box 1)
  - Wine Bottle. 29x27 cm diam. Pure California Port, product of Vina Winnery, Vina, Calif., ARCH-AM-2000-193 (Box 1)
  - Wine glass "50 Humanities Sciences 1948-1998" with paper souvenirs rolled and tied to stem of glass, ARCH-AM-1999-019 (Box 1)
  - Wine glass class of '62, 25th reunion in red letters. 82 x 6cm., ARCH-AM-1984-40 (Box 1)
  - Women's "S" society pin 1920, ARCH-AM-1978-10 (Box 1)
  - Women's athletic trophies, 36 trophies, various shapes and sizes, ARCH-AM-1984-60 (Box 1)
  - Women's bathing suits, ARCH-AM-1983-04 (Box 1)
    1. Bathing Suit: Blue and red, c. 1920 2. Bathing Suit: Gray, c. 1920, 2 pieces 3. Bathing Suit: Black and red, c. 1920.
  - Women's gym suits, ARCH-AM-1983-06 (Box 1)
    1. Gym suit: green dress and shorts, c. 1950; 2. Gym suit: green dress and shorts, c. 1950.
  - Wood carving of Stanford Roughs, c. 1915; 47x33cm, ARCH-AM-1984-22 (Box 1)
  - Wood splinter from goal post of Stanford v. USC football game, Nov. 11, 1933, ARCH-AM-1996-10 (Box 1)
  - Wood tie from Roble bridge, ARCH-AM-1978-05 (Box 1)
  - wooden abacus, ARCH-AM-1999-017 (Box 1)
  - Wooden Axe: painted red with "Stanford" in white letters on blade, ARCH-AM-1994-01 (Box 1)
  - Wooden bench kept outside a frat house with names carved on it, mostly from the 1940s-50s. Bench has plate: "Presented by James Choate '06", ARCH-AM-1997-007 (Box 1)
  - Wooden box for lantern slides from Fur Seal investigation with leather straps (PC 14), ARCH-AM-1980-27 (Box 1)
  - Wooden box with glass top that once held spike (the gold one?) from joining of railroads at Promontory Point. Detailed note on bottom of box., ARCH-AM-2005-008 (Box 1)
  - Wooden Pestle, 23cm high, ARCH-AM-1984-57 (Box 1)
  - Wooden plaque with image of basketball players, the year 1925, "Japanese Club," and garlands in 3d metal, ARCH-AM-2001-13 (Box 1)
  - Wooden rectangle possibly used as base for wall-hung phone, ARCH-AM-2003-014 (Box 1)
  - Wooden relay stick from 1917 UC-Stanford track meet (inscribed), ARCH-AM-1991-094 (Box 1)
  - Wooden sign "Keep off the cinders" (16 x 18 in.), ARCH-AM-1977-05 (Box 1)
  - wooden sign (in 3 parts): GAY PEOPLES UNION. Red letters on black boards., ARCH-AM-2000-012 (Box 1)
  - wooden sign: GLAS [Gays and Lesbians at Stanford] - 4 letters unpainted on white painted board, ARCH-AM-2000-013 (Box 1)
  - wooden sign: GPU [Gay People's Union] in brown letters on red board, with an arrow pointing up at an angle [presumably once directed visitors up the stairs at the Old Firehouse], ARCH-AM-2000-015 (Box 1)
  - Wooden tray (13 in. long) carved in shape of a fish, with eye, tail, and markings for scales and one fin., ARCH-AM-2007-022 (Box 1)
  - Woodworking tools made by Prof. Stanley. 7 rosewood planes and 2 rosewood scribes., ARCH-AM-1984-03 (Box 1)
  - Yell megaphone - "Stanford Indians", ca. 1950, 7 in., ARCH-AM-1992-15 (Box 1)
  - Yellow gold Patek Phillipe pocket watch given to Jane Stanford by Leland Stanford Jan. 1, 1868. Also includes spiral bound information packet on the watch (prepared in conjunction with its auction on ebay, 2005) with photos and copy of the authentication certificate from Patek Phillipe., ARCH-AM-2005-034 (Box 1)